Contact

s1759855@ed.ac.uk

+44 7722 003633

www.linkedin.com/in/sakib-a (LinkedIn)

www.sakib.tech (Personal Website)

Top Skills

Python

JavaScript

Java

Haskell

SQL

MATLAB

C/C++

Video Editing

Soft Skills

Management

Teamwork

Flexibility

Quick Learner

Confidence

Problem Solving

Sakib Ahamed

Penultimate Year BSc. Artificial Intelligence Student, The University of Edinburgh

Summary

I am a hardworking third year Artificial Intelligence student, with prior experience in financial technology and banking software. I have strong knowledge of the software development cycle, and proficiency in multiple programming languages. I work well under pressure, in teams, with a love for mathematics and problem solving. In my own time, I apply these skills to work on projects such as breast cancer detection with machine learning algorithms.

Education

The University of Edinburgh

Third Year, Bachelor of Science, Artificial Intelligence (2017 - 2021)

- Edinburgh Award for Global Insights Week (Singapore)
 I was selected for a fully funded program to explore different career paths through the experiences of alumni in Asia.
- Noteworthy Courses:

Applied Machine Learning (70%)

Reasoning and Agents (72%)

Data and Analysis (82%)

Foundations of Natural Language Processing (70%)

Societies and Activities:

Skydiving Society (Committee Member: Social Secretary)

CompSoc (Computer Science Society)

Archery Team

The Royal High School

(2011 - 2017)

- Scottish Highers AAAABC incl. As at Maths, Physics and English
- Dux of Mathematics
- James H Scott Award for Mathematics

Work Experience

Allatus Ltd

Junior Software Developer September 2018 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I am responsible for enhancing Allatus' FinTech web applications using JavaScript, HTML & Elasticsearch with the Dojo Toolkit. I work on both developing front-end algorithms and features, and fixing bugs. In addition, I update documentation, and create videos to ensure that all media content is both coherent and up to date with the latest builds of Allatus Unity. I am currently migrating to work on the back-end using C# and SQL databases.

Software Development Intern

May 2018 - September 2018 (5 months)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

Before being taken on as a full-time developer, I was selected for an internship with the software team.

The Three Sisters Pub & Restaurant

Runner

June 2017 - August 2017 (3 month)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

After secondary school, I worked in the fast-paced environment of The Three Sisters. I developed my time management skills, and learned to filter tasks by importance to complete my duties. These included personally introducing guests to the venue, dealing with a diverse range of customers.

Amazon

Event Assistant

May 2017 - May 2017 (1 month)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I took part in an Amazon technology showcase, involving AWS talks and Alexa demonstrations. I worked on networking and teamwork, as many tasks involved arranging the catering services and directing large groups of business delegates. I also had the chance to be a host and represent the company, which allowed me to further improve my interpersonal skills.

Boardwalk Beach Club Café

Waiter

June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom